<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Under Development | Ideawide]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.ideawide.com/categories/under-development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.ideawide.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-30T00:23:24+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.ideawide.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pasindu Perera]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surround sounds via ear phones]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ideawide.com/surround-sounds-via-ear-phones/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-10T18:20:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.ideawide.com/surround-sounds-via-ear-phones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I  recently saw that on a Samsung Galaxy Y, that users have an option to switch between normal speakers mode or to 5.1 speakers. This is possible as even there are 10 different speakers, everything is heard from our two ears. So if we can simulate the sound effect generated from those speakers, we can add as many as speakers and the head phones will simulate it. No need to get the physical speakers, all you need is the simulation. My idea is to develop an application (as a start an android) that enable user to configure the speaker position and the volume. Our software will simulate the effect through the ear phone. Simple and yet interactive application. We are working on to make it compatible with the standard media player or to be used with any other media player.
Currently we are developing this application and Lets see how far it will go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data communication over audio]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ideawide.com/data-communication-over-audio/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-03T18:27:49+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.ideawide.com/data-communication-over-audio</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Background</h2>

<p>Few years back blue-tooth was introduced to as a near field communication medium. What if we can use the audio clips to do the same thing?Technically speaking it is just to encode the data stream to a carrier signal and you are done with the encoding part.  For the de-cording little bit of forward error correction might be needed as there can be data losses in the medium. But it is not technically impossible, I would say it is technically simple.</p>

<h2>Possible uses</h2>

<p>If we can develop this as an mobile application most probably as android application there are plenty of uses with that app.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Use as a near field communication medium (Like blue-tooth). Difference being instead of sending here the app will play a music. and the receiver will grab it and decode it.</p></li>
<li><p>For rural communication. If a rural village is only covered by land lines a reporter there can send his digital media such as photos, video clips encoded on an audio stream and over the land line with out any complex equipments, and from the receiving end also without any complex expensive hardware user can get the media sent.</p></li>
<li><p>All most all the phones can record audio messages. So users can take data as recorded audio clip, even the handset does not support encoding and decoding.</p></li>
<li><p>Easily communicate over the mobile network. Does not need EDGE or HSDPA or 3G to communicate as well as hardware such as modems.</p></li>
<li><p>Communicate in between a computer and a phone with out a data cable or a blue-tooth/infra-red connectivity.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friend Utilities]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ideawide.com/friend-utilities/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-08T18:29:32+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.ideawide.com/friend-utilities</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an application that allows users to extend the functionality on Facebook. This basically and extended version of <a href="http://www.ideawide.com/appearing-offline/">Appearing Offline</a>. It has added support to add animated images to Facebook posts.</p>

<p>This application has more than 1,000+ Facebook installs</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tag Friends]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ideawide.com/tag-friends/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T18:23:52+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.ideawide.com/tag-friends</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tag their friends with different animation characters or movie heroes.</p>

<!-- more -->




<div class="alert alert-error">
Due to migration of Facebook Developer API this application is not currently functioning. It will be migrated very soon.
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Appear Offline]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.ideawide.com/appear-offline/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-20T20:24:52+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.ideawide.com/appear-offline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>This is an application that allows users to track their friends who are in limited online mode. It will show people who are online and the people who are in limited online along with the people who are offline.</p>

<div class="alert alert-error">
Due to migration of Facebook Developer API this application is not currently functioning. It will be migrated very soon.
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
